

ADDRESS: 192 Spencer Street 4B, Brooklyn, NY 11201

EMAIL: eric.fino@gmail.com

PHONE: 203.435.1340

PORTFOLIO: http://finomenon.com

PROFILE

I am a talented and hardworking technologist driven by a desire to create unique, exciting things. Throughout my 10+ year career in technology, I've had the fortune of working on some amazing projects. From Coca-Cola video mashup widgets to Nike and Converse product customization software, I've made things that both inspire creativity and increase business profits. As a developer, my strengths are in front-end web standards and responsive, adaptive design. As a manager and leader, my broad range of experiences in video production, visual design and user experience help me to facilitate communication within multidisciplinary teams, contributing to cohesive processes and high quality work.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Director: 360i, New York, NY (04/2015 - Present)

Oversee and provide technical leadership for integral digital projects, from ideation through deployment. Technical communication liaison for third-party IT departments, clients and internal team members. Develop business relationships with both clients and technology vendors. Contribute to scoping, scheduling and project planning. Ensure the efficiency of engineering teams by enforcing CI processes, coding best practices and proper use of task and code management tools. Acting as an advocate and evangelist for technology within the company and to our clients.

Technology Lead: R/GA, New York, NY (05/2013 - 04/2015)

Built and managed development teams for projects that ranged from enterprise-level, CMS-driven eCommerce websites to simple campaign micro-sites. Contributed to strategic planning, business development workshops, and managing client and tech partner relationships.

Senior Open Standards Developer: R/GA, New York, NY (08/2011 - 05/2013)

Lead developer and architect for adaptive, responsive websites and interactive, physical retail installations. Created prototypical experiences for RFPs. Specialized in mobile-first, responsive web development.

To view my full work history, please visit my linkedin profile. https://www.linkedin.com/in/finomenon

EDUCATION

MPS Interactive Telecommunications Program

New York University - Tisch School of the Arts 09/2004 - 05/2006

BFA Graphic Design

University of Massachusetts Lowell 09/1999 – 12/2003

Please continue to page 2 for skills.

Page: 1/2

SKILLS

Management Skills

Fogbugz, JIRA and Trello for task management Scoping, scheduling and project planning Scrum leader Agile methodologies Quality assurance

Developer Tools

Continuous Integration: Bamboo, Jenkins Version control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion NPM and Node.js (for local dev environments)

Languages and Libraries

HTML CSS Sass Javascript

Other languages

PHP MySQL

Other Skills

Photoshop Illustrator Final Cut Pro Technical liaison between IT and non-technical partners
Building client and vendor relationships

Team building and allocations management On-boarding and documentation

Task runners: Gulp, Grunt Hosting: AWS, Rackspace Vagrant and VBox

Demandware Wordpress JQuery Angular.js

Arduino Processing

Premier Blender

Adobe Media Encoder

References available upon request.